<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="ds_broker">• You need a broker to buy and sell shares on your behalf. \n• A brokerage account is like a bank account for investing. \n• Discount brokers provide cheap trading, but without the advice. \n\nSo you’ve decided to become an investor, but how do you go about actually buying shares? \n\nActually, legally, you can’t. \n\nShares can only be purchased by a licensed professional called a stockbroker. These are licensed and accredited professionals who ensure that trades are conducted with all the necessary legal and regulatory procedures. A stockbroker will buy and sell shares on your behalf in exchange for a fee. \n\nStockbrokers, therefore, act as a middleman between investors and the market. Much like if you’re feeling unwell, a doctor provides you a prescription, and the pharmacist fulfills that prescription. This is essentially the function of the stockbroker. \n\nIn the past, stockbrokers charged high fees and usually insisted on minimum deposits that were outside the realm of the average worker. These days, the internet has given birth to discount brokers that compete on pricing and usually have no minimum deposit restrictions. This has opened up investing to the masses. \n\nHowever, it comes with a downside. \n\nBrokers in the past also provided advice as part of their fee. Discount brokers provide no such service, which means that investing is very much a do-it-yourself endeavor. \n\nThat’s where MyWallSt comes in. We want to help educate and guide users throughout their investing life, giving them the tools to invest with confidence. \n\nHowever, the fact remains, you still need to engage a broker in order to buy and sell shares. \n\nIn the next lesson, we’ll look at how you go about setting up a brokerage account.</string>
    <string name="ds_brokerage">• There are some regulatory requirements to setting up an account\n• In order to set up a brokerage account, you will need to provide some basic information and answer some questions about your finances. \n• International investors may need to do some research into their own tax situation. \n\nSetting up a brokerage account is similar to setting up a bank account. However, the world of investing is a highly regulated one and brokers are required to gather a little more information than a bank. \n\nBefore you begin, you may want to do some research on what kind of brokerage you want. Brokers differentiate themselves by offering different fee structures or services. Some will allow you to invest in foreign companies, some will only permit you to invest in U.S. listed companies. Some will allow you to set up certain tax efficient account like Roth IRAs. \n\nWe have a close and deeply integrated relationship with the broker DriveWealth and recommend them to our users. However, the decision is yours. \n\nIn order to set up an account, you will need certain personal information like your name, address, and date of birth. Following this, you will be required to answer some simple questions regarding your employment status, income level, and investing experience. \n\nWhile some people may find these questions slightly intrusive, it’s an important element of the brokerage setup process. Brokers are required by law to “know their customer”, meaning they have to ensure that the products and services being offered are suitable to you. \n\nFinally, you’ll be asked to provide some documentation in order to prove who you are. \n\nThis will vary depending on where you live. A U.S. user might only be required to provide their social security number. An international user might be required to provide a photo of government-issued ID and proof of address. \n\nInternational investors must also complete a separate form called the W-8BEN, which is used to calculate what tax if any, you will have to pay in the U.S. on your gains. Many countries have a tax treaty with the US when it comes to this, but you should take the time to research your own situation.</string>
    <string name="ds_funding">• You need funds in your brokerage account to buy shares. \n• Funding options vary from country to country. \n• Having some cash sitting in your brokerage account can come in useful during a downturn. \n\nOnce you have a brokerage account set up and approved, you will need to fund it. \n\nFunding options vary from country to country and there are some costs associated with each method. \n\nAs costs are usually fixed, it may make sense to save up a bit before you fund in order to minimize “friction”—money that is associated with investing that doesn’t actually go into the shares you own. \n\nFor example, if it will cost you $4 to transfer money to your account, sending $20 will mean you’re already down 20%. That’s not an efficient way to invest. \n\nRather, you should think about saving up and sending $200. That way you’re only down 2%. With fixed costs, the more money you transfer, the less detrimental these costs are to your overall returns. \n\nIf you want to be serious about investing regularly, it might be a good idea to set up an automatic transfer with your bank. That way you can have money transferred into your brokerage account just after your wages come in every month. This will ensure that you stay disciplined and don’t end up using those extra funds for needless purchases. \n\nRemember, just because the money is in your brokerage account, that doesn’t mean you need to invest it right away. It’s always a good idea to keep some cash in your brokerage account in case there is a certain market downturn. This way you can invest in some great companies at a discount. However, don’t leave all your funds in cash. Waiting for the market to dip can easily lead you to missing out on big gains.</string>
    <string name="ds_first_share">• Your first investment should be a company that you are interested in. \n• You don’t need to put all your money in right away. \n• Keeping an investment journal is a great way to learn as you go. \n\nNow that your broker account is set up and funded, you’re all ready to buy your first share. \n\nThis is where a lot of novice investors get stuck. \n\nOn many occasions we have users contact us saying they can’t decide on what stocks to start off with, concerned that they don’t know enough or that they’ll lose money. \n\nThe important thing to remember here is that investing is a life-long pursuit. Your first stock doesn’t have to be the perfect investment, backed by hundreds of hours of in-depth research. \n\nGetting started is what’s most important here. \n\nIf you’re not feeling confident, invest a small amount (nothing that is going to hurt you financially) in a company that interests you. As previously mentioned, Bedrock stocks like Apple and Google are safer investments than small-cap companies. \n\nOwning shares in a company will foster your interest in that company. Suddenly, you’ll find yourself reading up more on the business, getting to know the managers, and understanding how it works. \n\nA great tip is to start an investment journal with your very first purchase. \n\nSimply write down the date of your purchase along with any thoughts that led you to this decision. For example, you may like the CEO and believe in his long-term vision for the company. Obviously, this means you’re going to have to read up on the CEO and find out what that vision is. This is an important part of the learning process. If you haven’t got any reasons to buy the shares, then obviously this isn’t the right stock for you. \n\nYou’ll find these notes incredibly helpful further down the line. You’ll be able revisit the first stages of your investment thesis and examine what you got right, and possibly what you got wrong.</string>
    <string name="ds_monitoring">• Don’t worry about checking the stock price every day. \n• Keep tabs on how the company is performing via the news and company press releases. \n• Read the company’s quarterly reports to get better insight into the business. \n\nNow that you’ve bought your first stock, you’re officially an investor. \n\nCongratulations! \n\nHopefully, this will be the first step in a long and profitable journey for you. \n\nNow you need to start monitoring your investment to see how it’s performing. \n\nIn our other app, MyWallSt, your stock will be automatically added to your portfolio so you can track its performance. However, checking the stock price every day isn’t really helpful. \n\nIt’s a far better use of your time to keep tabs on how the business is performing. \n\nIn the Focus section of the MyWallSt app, you’ll find daily updates about the businesses we recommend written in-house by our analysts. This is a great place to start. \n\nMost companies will also send out press releases regarding any important news about the business. You can subscribe to these updates on the investor relations section of their corporate websites. \n\nFinally, you should find out when the company is set to send out their quarterly earnings release. Every public company in the U.S. publishes one every 3 months. In it, management will give a summary of what’s occurred over the previous quarter. Some also give insights into their future plans, and possibly even how much they expect to earn in the coming year. \n\nFollowing these steps will have you set up to become an informed and successful investor in no time. Once you get into the swing of things, you can simply repeat the process to build a diversified portfolio of great companies.\n\nGood luck on your investing journey.</string>
</resources>