<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="dil_first_stock">• No one can time the market, so don’t bother trying. \n• Invest when you have the funds to do so in a company you will enjoy following. \n• Large-cap bedrocks are a safe first investment to get you started. \n\nSo many early investors feel like they need to wait for the right time to get into the market. Everyone fears the next downturn and there is a constant worry that the day they buy their first stock will be the day that everything will come crashing down. \n\nThe great thing about this problem is that it’s actually a pretty easy thing to fix. \n\nStep 1: Don’t worry and invest when you have the money to do so. \n\nAnd that’s it. Always remember this when you feel the need to hold back or wait and see: \n\nTime in the market is a lot more important than timing the market. \n\nThe reason you shouldn’t worry about timing the market is a fairly simple one. You can’t. No one can. Not even the greatest financial scholar or the highest paid Wall Street advisor. \n\nIf you listen to the talking heads and stock advisors; you’ll often hear them talking about a good time to buy or sell. This usually happens after the company has had some major news or released a quarter’s earnings report. \n\nThese kinds of events usually shake the price of a stock around a bit - leading the speculators to swoop in to try and make a quick buck. Over the long run, these minor movements will have very little effect on your investment. \n\nYour first stock should be a company that you love and believe in. It should be one that you’re going to enjoy reading about and watching grow over the many years you intend to own it. \n\nWe recommend you choose a large-cap bedrock for your first investment. Think about companies like Google, Amazon, Disney or Starbucks. These companies aren’t going anywhere any time soon. They are good stocks to build your portfolio on before you start to diversify with smaller companies.</string>
    <string name="dil_diversifying">• Diversifying means spreading the risk across a number of investments. \n• You should aim for a balanced portfolio with companies of various sizes. \n• You can also diversify between sectors, countries and asset classes. \n\nThere are no angels on Wall Street and there are even fewer sure things. Remember that no matter how much research you put into an investment, there’s always a risk you’ll lose your money. \n\nYou can lessen the risk by investing in great companies that have proven track records, like those in our showroom. Bedrock companies like Apple or Google are very unlikely to go bankrupt anytime soon, but it’s still a good idea to cover yourself against all possibilities. \n\nThis is where diversifying comes in. This means spreading your investment over a range of companies and sectors. After all, why put all your eggs in one basket when there are so many great companies to invest in. \n\nSpreading yourself too thin will lead to average returns. You should aim to own around 12 different companies within your first year of investing. \n\nHere are a few ways you can easily diversify your portfolio: \n\nMarket Cap\n\nYou can diversify by investing in companies of various sizes. Investing in bigger companies comes with less risk, but also with less potential for growth. Smaller companies are riskier but provide greater potential for big returns. A smart investor looks for balance. Cover the risk of investing in small cap companies by diversifying with bigger, safer, investments. \n\nSectors\n\nDon’t over rely on one sector. If all your investments are in oil companies and the price of oil drops, your whole portfolio is going to take a hit. Different sectors respond differently to economic conditions. A drop in the price of oil will hurt oil companies but will benefit FedEx and airlines. So spread your investment over varying sectors to ensure a major economic trend or geopolitical event can’t hurt your entire portfolio. \n\nGeography\n\nEconomies are in a constant state of flux. When the economy is down, consumer spending is down. You can protect yourself by investing in companies that have exposure to foreign markets. Coca-Cola is an American company that makes most of its money overseas. A struggling US economy is going to hurt Coca-Cola’s earnings, but not as much as it will hurt Chipotle, who operate primarily in the States. \n\nAsset Classes\n\nAs well as stocks, you can spread your risk by investing in things like real estate or bonds. We believe that younger investors should look to stocks as their main source of investment, simply because they provide the greatest returns. As you get older, you may want to invest in less risky government bonds to ensure your portfolio is protected and you have a steady income stream.</string>
    <string name="dil_build_portfolio">• Take your time building up your portfolio - aim for between six and twelve stocks. \n• Keep saving and add regularly to your positions. \n• Dollar cost averaging eliminates emotion from the process and will make you a more disciplined investor. \n\nBuilding a portfolio isn’t something that should happen overnight. The day you buy your first stock is the day you become an investor - you have the rest of your life to build a solid portfolio. \n\nA good long-term investor should think in terms of planting trees, not throwing darts. Over time, that first stock should grow into a basket of great companies that represent what you believe and where you think the world is headed. \n\nIn order for that to happen, you have to keep saving and keep investing. \n\nEvery investor has their own way of building up a portfolio, but to get you started, here are two popular methods. \n\nFull/Half Position\n\nDecide based on your personal finances what is the most you are willing to put into a single company. This could be anything from a few hundred dollars to a few hundred thousand. \n\nCall this a full position and save with the goal of adding several full positions to your portfolio over time. \n\nIf you want to buy more companies in a shorter amount of time, buy twice as many half positions and turn them into full positions when you’re able. \n\nFor example, you like the look of Facebook and decide a full position is $500. Once you have that saved, you open up a full position by purchasing $500 worth of Facebook. In two months, you have another $500 saved. You could start another full position in Mastercard. Alternatively, you could split the $500 and buy two half positions in Mastercard and Zillow. The next time you save up $500, you can turn these into full positions rather than opening up another position. \n\nAs you grow as an investor, you’ll realize there are some companies you want to open full positions in right away and others you will want to be more cautious with. \n\nDollar Cost Averaging\n\nIn dollar cost averaging, you choose a few stocks and buy a set amount every month or every quarter. \n\nThe beauty of dollar cost averaging is that you can build up a large diversified portfolio in a short amount of time. \n\nIt also removes emotion from the process, as you purchase the same dollar amount every month regardless of price. If the stock has gone down, you get more shares for the same amount of money.</string>
    <string name="dil_risk_reward">• Risk is the price you pay for returns.\n• A diverse portfolio should include some risky investments along with safer large-caps. \n• The younger you are; the more risk you should be willing to take. \n\nHaving a diverse portfolio means more than just picking stocks from different sectors. You have to be willing to balance those big companies with riskier investments. That will depend a lot on your tolerance for risk, something your age should play a big part in. \n\nThe younger you are, the more risk you should be willing to take when it comes to investing. Someone in their early twenties has another four decades to make money, as opposed to someone in their late fifties, who is gearing up for retirement. \n\nPeter Lynch, one of the greatest investors of our time, coined the phrase “ten baggers.” This is a stock in which you make ten times your original investment. It sounds crazy, but actually these are fairly common in the world of investing. \n\nThe problem is that you have to be willing to take some risks in order to get them. Not all your risky investments will work out. The great thing about ten baggers is that you only need one to make up for nine total duds if you split your investments evenly. \n\nTen baggers are the stocks that can dramatically change your financial future and they’re often sitting right under our noses. \n\nA great example is Apple. If those people who bought the first iPod had bought $399 worth of Apple stock instead, it would be worth $36,480 today. That’s a ninety-bagger. \n\nApple is still a great stock, but it will never reach that level of growth again. To get that kind of growth, you have to be willing to take some risks. \n\nRisk is the price you have to pay if you want those outstanding rewards. There are no safe growth stories out there; you have to be willing to take a chance on them when you see them. \n\n</string>
    <string name="dil_timeline">• Investing success is not measured in minutes, months, or even a year. \n• Successful investors remain calm when everyone around them is freaking out. \n• Cultivate a temperament that resists the urges that get other people into trouble. \n\nThe Two Secrets All Great Investors Share\n\nThis lesson is a Jedi Mind Trick that will turn you into an investor, rather than a speculator. \n\nFirst, here’s what you don’t need: more money, a higher IQ or superb market timing. \n\nNope, the secrets are simply timeline and temperament. \n\nTimeline\n\nInvesting in stocks requires a minimum five-year time horizon. Think of it like sending some of your money away to work overseas for a while. You can give it a call to check in on it, but you really just need to let it do its own thing. \n\nInvesting success is not measured in minutes, months, or even a year. If you look back at history and study how investing fortunes were made, you’ll find it wasn’t by jumping in and out of stocks based on fear and greed, but by buying great businesses and investing in them over the long haul. \n\nThen, you can expect to be rewarded over time through share price appreciation, dividends and share repurchases. \n\nTemperament\n\nSuccessful investors have the ability to remain calm and levelheaded when everyone around them is freaking out. That mindset makes the difference between investors who consistently outperform the market and investors who get lucky once in a while. \n\nIf you can keep your emotions in check and ignore the occasional (and inevitable) market panic, you’ll be able to hang on rather than selling out at the worst times. \n\nMake all investment decisions with a cool head after letting new information or temporary market swings sink in. Sometimes the best action to take is no action at all. \n\nWarren Buffet famously said, “Success in investing doesn’t correlate with IQ … what you need is the temperament to control the urges that get other people into trouble."</string>
    <string name="dil_mistakes">• Everyone makes mistakes throughout their investing life. \n• Learn from your mistakes or you’ll never become a great investor. \n• Doing nothing is the biggest mistake you can make. \n\nYou’re going to make mistakes when you get into investing. Everyone does, from Warren Buffett to George Soros. Being a good investor means you learn from your mistakes and try to mitigate your losses. \n\nIn order to help you avoid the most common pitfalls, here’s a quick list of some basic mistakes that new investors make. When you notice yourself about to make one, you can step back, regroup and get back on track toward becoming the brilliant, patient and cool-headed investor you’re meant to be. \n\nDoing nothing\n\nThere are no guarantees in the market. Except one: Not investing at all will not provide for a comfortable retirement. \n\nRemember, time in the market is much more important than timing the market. You don’t need to make a huge decision regarding your life-savings - buy one share in a company that you love. After that, you can start thinking about the bigger picture and start diversifying. \n\nInvesting for the short term\n\nThe caveat to part one is don’t invest with money you don’t have. \n\nBuying one share to get you off the mark is all well and good, but don’t go investing huge sums of money that you may need in the next year. Far too often, novice investors throw all their savings into stocks thinking they can sell them off whenever they need the money back. \n\nThis isn’t a bank account. If you need the money in the middle of a downturn, you may have sell for a loss. \n\nPlaying it safe\n\nIf you’re young, don’t go investing solely in low risk, low yield stocks. You’ve got years to weather the dips in the market and reap the huge rewards. \n\nOlder investors don’t have that luxury. You know the expression “time is money?” Nowhere is that more true than in the stock market. Use your time to your advantage and invest in companies with the potential for long term growth. \n\nTry to invest in upcoming megatrends, like green energy, and find the leaders in the industry to buy into. \n\nPlaying it risky\n\nConversely, don’t go throwing all your money into risky companies - particularly overhyped stocks without solid business models or sound leadership. \n\nSpread the risk across a few companies and sectors to cover yourself in the event of a downturn and have a few bedrock shares from larger companies to keep your portfolio balanced. \n\nFollowing the crowd\n\nIf following the crowd worked, we’d all be millionaires. \n\nYou’re going to go through periods where every fiber of your being is telling you to sell a stock you still believe in because of some temporary slump. Bad earnings report here and there isn’t going to be the downfall of a great company. \n\nStock prices go up and down - stick to your guns and over time you’ll reap the rewards of a long term investment strategy. Keep changing your mind and your returns will be eaten away at by trading fees.</string>
    <string name="dil_sell">• It’s impossible to know the perfect time to sell. \n• Deciding when to sell is a much harder process than deciding when to buy. \n• If you believe you own part of a great business, don’t sell. \n\n“No one rings a bell at the top and no one rings a bell at the bottom” is an old saying on Wall Street. \n\nThat means it’s impossible to know when a stock has hit the bottom or when it’s hit the top. \n\nWe’ve already covered when you should buy a stock, but often much harder in the process is deciding when to sell a stock. \n\nThe best stocks are the ones you never want to sell. If you buy a good company at a good price, the value will continue to increase over your lifetime. Then the only question you have to ask yourself is do I want to realize some of those gains in order to buy something else, like a house or a new car. \n\nOther times, we may believe some of our own stocks are overvalued and decide to sell in order to move that money into an undervalued stock. \n\nHowever, that doesn’t always happen and sometimes we have to sell a stock that has not performed as we had hoped. \n\nThere are three questions you can ask yourself before you pull the trigger and sell a losing stock. \n\n1. “Was I wrong?” Sometimes you buy for the wrong reasons. Sometimes your idea doesn’t work out. If that happens, sell and move on. We all make mistakes. Accept it. Learn from it. \n\n2. “Has something changed?” Maybe you were right at the time, but something has changed. Has a visionary leader left the company? Have they failed to innovate and lost their sustainable competitive advantage? That’s when it’s time to sell. \n\n3. “Do I still believe in this company?” No matter what happens, if you still believe you own part of a great business… don’t sell. Often times, the market loses faith in a company based on a poor earnings report or some temporary problem. A long-term investor can weather these storms and wait for their stock to rebound. \n\n</string>
</resources>