<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="db_what_is_stock">• A stock is a piece of ownership in a company.\n• In the short-term, share price changes based on the fickle opinion of the masses. \n• In the long-term, a company’s true value is reflected in its share price. \n\nMore than just a slip of paper (or a computer record these days), a stock is a stake in a living, breathing business in which you share the rewards and the risks alike. \n\nIn order to raise capital, companies issue stocks for sale to the general public, which are then traded as the value rises and falls. Stocks are traded on various exchanges all around the world, the largest being the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE). \n\nIn the short term, a share price moves based on the opinion of the crowd: those people looking to buy or sell. When there are more people looking to buy, up the price goes. This is usually fickle, because the news of the day influences what the world thinks about certain stocks. \n\nOver the long term, however, a company’s true value is reflected in its price, that’s why time – more than anything else – is the critical ingredient of successful investing. \n\nAs part-owner, you are entitled to a share of that company’s profits and assets. You also have a say in how that business is run. How much of those profits you have claim to and how much influence you have depends on the amount of stocks you own relative to the total number of shares issued. \n\nStocks are the backbone of a good investment portfolio and have proven to outperform every other form of investment in the long run.</string>
    <string name="db_ticker_symbols">• A ticker symbol is a 3, 4 or 5 letter abbreviation that easily identifies every public company.\n• Stocks traded on the NYSE have symbols with up to 3 letters, like MA (Mastercard).\n• Stocks traded on the NASDAQ have symbols with 4 letters, like MSFT (Microsoft).\n\nWhat is a Ticker Symbol?\n\nA ticker, or stock symbol, is a unique 3, 4 or 5 letter abbreviation assigned to every public company for identification purposes. All tickers use only capital letters.\n\nThink of tickers as nicknames. Sometimes, they can be exactly the same as the brand name – like IBM.\n\nSometimes they can even be clever – Like Anheuser-Busch choosing the ticker symbol BUD or Harley Davidson going with HOG.\n\nA 2007 academic study actually showed that stocks with creative ticker symbols tend to have higher returns than the overall market!\n\nStocks traded on the New York Stock Exchange have symbols with up to three letters – like T (AT&amp;T), DO (Diamond Offshore Drilling) and LUV (Southwest Airlines).\n\nStocks traded on the NASDAQ usually have four-letter symbols – like MSFT (Microsoft).\n\nIf you see a five-letter ticker symbol that ends with the letter X, that is how you can automatically recognize a mutual fund – like UUPIX (for Profunds UltraEmerging Markets). Beware that mutual funds don’t actually trade on any exchange the way stocks do, though.</string>
    <string name="db_public_offerings">• An IPO (Initial Public Offering) is when companies sell their stock for the first time to the public.\n• A company uses an underwriter to determine the best price at which to sell their shares.\n• IPOs let companies raise a lot of money they don’t have to pay back.\n\n<u>What does “going public” mean?</u>\n\nAn initial public offering, known as an IPO, is when company stock is sold for the very first time to the general public. \n\nThis is the same day the company gets “listed” on a stock exchange. \n\nFrom this day forward, it’s no longer a small circle of company founders who own the business. It now also belongs to the public. \n\n<u>Who determines the price?</u>.\n\nThe company hires an underwriter. An underwriter’s job is to get all those initial shares out the door. To do that, they can either analyze the company and slap a price on it (“fixed pricing”), or they can call around to the biggest investors in the country and gauge the demand (“book building”). \n\nOnce the shares are on the open market, though, their value is determined only by market sentiment, which is the way investors feel about the company. \n\n<u>Why do companies go public?</u>\n\nMost importantly, to raise money without asking a bank for it. See, the money that a company gets from an IPO never needs to be paid back. \n\nThe company can use that money to grow operations, buy new equipment or even acquire other companies. \n\nOriginal shareholders also like the idea of spreading the risk around. After going public, the owners of a company can cash in some profits while holding onto just a percentage of the company.</string>
    <string name="db_stock_exchanges">• Stock exchanges (NYSE, NASDAQ) operate within a geographical stock market (US, Japanese, etc.). \n• Shares for sale have an “ask” price and buyers pay a “bid” price. \n• The gap between the bid and ask is the “spread,” a commission paid to exchanges. \n\n<u>Stock Market Vs. Stock Exchange</u>\n\nThe stock market means all stock exchanges within a geographical region. For example, the US stock market or the Indian stock market.\n\nWithin each market, there are multiple stock exchanges.\n\nA stock exchange is like a supermarket for shares. Think of the NASDAQ and New York Stock Exchange as Sam’s Club and Costco. They sell similar things and they have to compete for customers. The more trades they process; the more money they make.\n\nAny share you want to buy or sell will be listed on an exchange. As the buyer (or seller), it makes no difference to you which one it is. When you go online and place your order, the computer will route your trade to the correct exchange within seconds.\n\nExchanges pair up buyers and sellers (just like eBay). When shares are for sale, they have an asking price, called the “ask price.”\n\nBuying shares is like being the bidder on eBay, so the buyer has to pay a “bid price.”\n\nThere will always be a gap between the two (usually a few pennies). This is called the “spread.” That spread is how the exchanges make money. It’s their commission.</string>
    <string name="db_sandp">• The Standard &amp; Poor’s 500 is a selection of 500 stocks that represent the entire stock market. \n• When people talk about “beating the market,” the market is The S&amp;P 500. \n• If the Samp;P 500 goes up 10% and your portfolio goes up 13%, you beat the market by 3%.\n\n<u>What is the S&amp;P 500?</u>\n\nTurn on any financial television network and you’ll almost certainly hear someone mention “The S&amp;P” within 5 minutes. \n\nYou’ll also hear professional investors talk about “beating the market.” \n\nSo what are they talking about? \n\nThe S&amp;P 500, or Standard &amp; Poor’s 500, is a selection (aka index) of 500 stocks that are a microcosm of the entire stock market. It is the most commonly followed index and is considered a good indicator of the health of the U.S. economy. \n\nIt’s been around since 1923, but the 500 companies have changed since then. \n\nYou’ll often hear people talking about “beating the market.” “The market” in this case means the S&amp;P 500. For example, if the S&amp;P rose 13% in one year, but your stock portfolio went up 17% that same year, you beat the market by 4%. Good job! \n\nBeating the market is seen as the holy grail of stock investing. \n\nThere are plenty of other indexes that track various sections of the stock market both in the States and worldwide. The Dow Jones Industrial Average is similar to the S&amp;P 500 except it focuses on 30 companies. The FTSE 100 tracks the UK stock market, while the Nikkei 250 tracks Japan. \n\nThere are indexes for specific industries and even very specialized indexes to track things like “ethical companies.”</string>
    <string name="db_company_size">• To determine the size of a company, look at “market capitalization” (market cap, for short). \n• Market Cap = Number of shares outstanding multiplied by share price. \n• Market cap sizes range from nano, micro, small, mid, large and mega. \n\nNew investors often fall into the trap of equating share price with value. In reality the two are completely independent of each other. The share price is actually of very little consequence. As we will see later with stock splits, a company’s share price is dependent on how many shares are in the market at any given time. \n\nLet’s take the example of McDonald’s and Chipotle Mexican Grill. A stock in Chipotle currently costs around six times that of McDonald’s. So which is the bigger company? \n\nChipotle is a great company that has been expanding rapidly, but it’s nowhere near competing at McDonalds’ level just yet. To get the figures, we look at the market capitalization of each company. We can work that out by looking at the current share price and multiplying it by the number of shares in the market. \n\nChipotle has around 31 million shares in the market right now, making the company worth $18.5 billion. McDonald’s on the other hand has almost a billion shares, giving them a value (or market cap) of over $100 billion. \n\nSo what does this mean for investors? Shouldn’t you just invest in the most valuable companies? \n\nIt all depends on what your goal is as an investor. The more valuable companies are much safer investments. Apple, Google, and Disney aren’t going anywhere anytime soon. You’re pretty much guaranteed that you won’t lose all your money on these guys. \n\nThe flipside is that these companies aren’t going to grow as fast as smaller companies like Chipotle, iRobot, and SolarCity. These companies have more room to expand and therefore could see huge rises over the next few years. Of course, that also makes them riskier investments. \n\nSo you’re making a trade-off between risk and reward. The more volatile a company, the greater the potential for growth. The more secure a company, the less the chance of quadrupling your money. \n\nThere are six levels of market capitalization. \n\n• Mega Cap (least risk/slowest growth): $200 billion and greater\n• Large Cap: $10-$200 billion\n• Mid Cap: $2 billion to $10 billion\n• Small Cap: $300 million to $2 billion\n• Micro Cap: $50 million to $300 million\n• Nano Cap (most risk/fastest growth): Under $50 million</string>
    <string name="db_penny_stocks">• Penny stocks trade for very low figures - sometimes a fraction of a penny per share. \n• They do not have to meet the same standards as companies listed on the NYSE and NASDAQ. \n• They are susceptible to price manipulation and should be avoided. \n\nOne of the most frequent questions asked by new investors is related to penny stocks. These are stocks traded on the smaller exchanges or “pink pages”. \n\nPenny stocks can be bought for next to nothing per share, sometimes a fraction of a penny. Investors often think, wow, it couldn’t go lower than that. Trust us… it can, and very often it will. \n\nLet’s start by going through why penny stocks are a bad idea to begin with. \n\nFirstly, they don’t have to comply with the same accounting standards as companies listed on the NASDAQ or NYSE. Often times, companies are penny stocks simply because they can’t comply with these standards or meet the minimum requirements of these exchanges. That’s not the kind of company you should be investing in. \n\nThese companies are not covered by Wall Street analysts, meaning there is very little historic or current information available. \n\nFinally, these companies are incredibly volatile. This is what draws novice investors to penny stocks - the potential for massive short term growth. Keep in mind, it works both ways and penny stocks can quickly become worthless. \n\nPenny stocks are highly susceptible to price manipulation. This is where the pump and dump comes in. A pump and dump involves one investor buying up a large quantity of penny stocks. They then spread hype about the company (claiming to have inside information) through newsletters, message boards, cold calling, etc. \n\nInvestors start buying (pumping) up the stock, making the price rise and pushing more and more investors to invest. The original investor then sells or ‘dumps’ his large amount of stock and the price plummets. \n\nPenny stocks may seem attractive for young investors, but really they are a complete gamble. Investing in established companies with brilliant track records is a much more secure and lucrative place for your money.</string>
    <string name="db_dividends">• Some companies pay out regular dividends to their shareholders. \n• These companies are usually past the initial high growth stage. \n• Companies that pay dividends are good investments for people approaching retirement as they provide a steady stream of income. \n\nSome (not all) companies “reward” their investors with dividend payments on a monthly, quarterly, or yearly basis. \n\nYou’ll often hear analysts talk about companies that are “good to their shareholders” - they’re talking about companies that pay dividends. \n\nFor some investors, this is a deal breaker when it comes to choosing stocks. \n\nMakes sense right? Why would you invest in a company like Under Armour that pays no dividend when you can invest in Costco, or Coca Cola, who pay them out regularly? \n\nIt all depends on what kind of investor you are and what you expect from your portfolio. \n\nWhen a company reaches the point that they are regularly profitable and have paid off all their debt, they have four choices for what to do with the money: \n\n• Reinvest in the company and try to expand either through new markets or new products. \n• Sit on the cash so as to build up reserves. \n• Payout a dividend to the shareholders. \n• Buy back shares in the company. \n\nWhen a company chooses not to reinvest; they’re essentially saying that they’ve reached the point where substantial growth is no longer possible. So they pay out a regular dividend to keep the shareholders happy. \n\nIf you’re mature and approaching retirement, dividend-paying companies could be a good choice for you. The steady source of income can help you through retirement and the stocks can be passed down to your children. Companies that pay dividends are usually less volatile, as the regular dividend provides confidence to investors. \n\nHowever, in a downturn, companies may have to decrease or eliminate their dividend. This is a massive red flag for investors, who will jump ship at the mere suggestion of a dividend cut, which will then cause a reduction of the share price. Now you have shareholders who’ve lost capital and are seeing their steady source of income slashed. Not a good mix. \n\nYounger investors really shouldn’t concern themselves too much with dividends. With time on your side, you should be looking for companies with plenty of room to grow their business and, in turn, your investment. \n\nIf you want to find a nice middle ground, look for companies that engage in stock buy backs. When a company buys back its own stock, it not only increases the share price, but is a massive show of confidence in the business from the people who know most about the potential challenges and opportunities ahead.</string>
    <string name="db_stock_splits">• When a stock splits, the share price goes down and the number of shares goes up. \n• If a company splits 2-for-1, 500 shares at $20 becomes 1,000 shares at $10. \n• Splits make stocks more liquid and more affordable to everyday investors. \n\nHow is it possible to turn 1 million shares into 2 million overnight? \n\nBy doing a stock split! \n\nIf you own 50 shares of Wal-Mart (WMT) and the company does a 2-for-1 stock split, you now have 100 shares of WMT stock. \n\nDid you just double your money? \n\nNo, because in a 2-for-1 stock split, the share price gets cut in half. \n\nSo, what’s the point of all this? \n\nIf one share of Priceline (PCLN), for example, costs $1,000, then only investors with over a thousand dollars could become shareholders. So, the thoughtful chaps running Priceline might make a decision to split shares 3-for-1. So in this example, one share is worth $1000 before the split and afterward there are three shares worth $333.33 each -- same difference. However, now there are more shares on the market, making it even easier for people to buy and sell them. \n\nDuring a stock split, the value of the company never changes, but it makes the company look more affordable to small investors – and they start buying. This can boost demand and drive up the stock price for a short time following the split. \n\nThere is also something called a reverse stock split. \n\nJust as a company like Google (GOOG) may want to seem more affordable, smaller companies sometimes want to appear more expensive and, in turn, more reputable. \n\nA stock that is valued at $1 per share can do a reverse 5-for-1 split and end up with a $5 stock and 1/5 as many shares on the market.</string>
    <string name="db_order_types">• A market order means buying and selling at the best available price. \n• A limit order means buying and selling at a predetermined price. \n• Stops and limits can be used to protect investors from market crashes. \n\nThere are three main types of order you should know about before getting involved in the stock market. If you want to keep things simple, you can stick to placing market orders. \n\n<u>Market Orders</u>\n\nMarket orders guarantee your order will get filled at the best price. It might not be filled at the price you want, but it will get filled. So let’s say you want to buy 100 shares in Twitter (TWTR). You’re investing for the long term, so a slight difference in price isn’t really a concern for you. You should place a market order and your broker will fill it at the best price the shares are available for. \n\nIf you want to exert a little more control over the process, here are the other things you can do, using Twitter stock as an example: \n\n<u>Limit Orders</u>\n\nLimit orders let you buy or sell at a predetermined price. Here’s an example of limit orders in action. \n\nBuy 100 TWTR, Limit = $25. $25 is the maximum you are prepared to pay for one share Sell 100 TWTR, Limit = $25. $25 is the minimum you are prepared to accept for one share\n\nLet’s say you want to buy 100 Twitter shares, but think it’s overvalued at the moment. You can set a limit order to buy the shares when they reach a lower price. Now, you might be wrong and the shares never reach that low - which means the order will never be filled. \n\nStop Market Orders\n\nStop market orders let you sell as a market order once a predetermined price has been reached. It essentially sets a trigger to release your shares to the market. \n\nStop Market 100 TWTR at $25. Once your TWTR shares hit $25 they are put on the market for sale. \n\nYou may get more or less than $25, depending on which way the market is moving. But $25 is the “trigger” that activates a sale. \n\nStop Limit Orders\n\nStop limit orders are the same as a Stop Market except you also set a price below which you will not sell. \n\nStop Limit 100 TWTR at $25, Limit = $23 – When your TWTR shares hit $25 they are put on the market for sale, but you will not accept anything less than $23 per share. \n\nWhen would I use these order types? \n\nLet’s say you take a month-long, off-the-grid trip to the Himalayas and can’t watch your stocks during that time. You might think about entering a stop market order before you leave. This would protect you from a major loss in case the market was to crash while you’re away. \n\nBeware that as your orders get fancier, your broker’s commissions may go higher. Double check before you execute a stop or limit order that it’s worth it. Even with all these options (and more) available to you, when buying and holding great companies over the long-term, simple market orders are usually the best way to go.</string>
    <string name="db_margins">• Margin accounts allow investors to buy stocks using borrowed funds. \n• Margin is a cash cow for brokers, but can cost an investor a lot in interest. \n• A broker can force you to liquidate your margin positions before you are ready to sell. \n\nAfter you’ve been with your broker for a while, they may offer you the chance to buy stocks on margin. A normal cash account only lets you buy as much stock as you have cash on hand to pay for. A margin account lets you purchase stocks with borrowed money. Cue the red flags and warning sirens! \n\nWhile margin accounts can increase your returns, they also greatly increase your risk. \n\n“But my broker suggested margin!” \n\nNo surprise there. Brokers stand to make a lot of money off margin accounts. How? By charging interest on the borrowed funds. And since margin gives you more (borrowed) money with which to buy stocks, it generates greater commission fees. \n\nDon’t bite if you’re told that margin accounts increase your "buying power." Buying on margin only enhances your "borrowing power." You’ll have to pay all that margin money back at some point. And if the stocks you bought on margin have decreased in value when the piper comes to call, you may not have the money to repay. \n\nAt that point, your broker reserves the right to liquidate positions in your account to cover the loan. This can leave you with large losses you could have recovered if you had been able to hold onto your positions as they rebounded. \n\nUltimately, the person who gains the most control in a margin account is your broker, not you. For them, margin is a cash cow; for you, a double-edged sword.</string>
    <string name="db_short_selling">• Just like you can bet on a stock rising; you can bet on it declining. \n• This is called short selling or shorting. \n• Technically short selling can lead to unlimited losses. \n\nDisclaimer: We at MyWallSt in no way endorse short selling. Some people make a lot of money doing it, but really, it’s something that should be left to the speculators and day traders. This chapter is purely to educate you on the practice. \n\nJust like you can invest in a company and make a return when the value goes up, you can bet against a company and make money when its value declines. It’s called short selling. \n\nTo do this you’ll need a margin account with your broker (we already warned you not to get one of those), as technically you could incur unlimited losses. \n\nWhen you short sell, you borrow a stock from your broker using credit. If the stock price drops 10%, you can then buy the stock at the lower price and make a profit on the difference. If the stock price goes up, however, you may be forced to buy it at the higher price to pay back the owner. \n\nSince the lowest a stock price can go is zero, when you buy a stock, the most you are going to lose is the money you’ve invested. When short selling, there is no limit to what you could lose, as the price could continue to rise indefinitely. \n\nWhen you short a stock you are not entitled to any dividends or shareholders rights, as you are only borrowing the stock. To further complicate things, if demand for the stock goes up, your broker can force you to return it if the original owner wants to sell. So even if the price has gone up, but you still expect it to drop, you might have no choice in holding onto the stock and be forced to incur a loss.</string>
    <string name="db_extended_hours">• The NYSE and NASDAQ are open for regular trading from 9:30 a.m. to 4:00 p.m. EST. \n• Some brokers allow you to trade after hours, but there are far fewer people to buy from and sell to. \n• Less liquidity and higher spreads mean it can be hard to get the price you want. \n\n<u>Extended Hours Trading</u>\n\nWe live in a world where nearly everything is available 24/7. \n\nSo why not trade stocks around the clock too? \n\nThe truth is, you absolutely can. Trouble is, there are risks and dangers you need to be aware of first. \n\nThe New York Stock Exchange and NASDAQ are both open from 9:30 a.m. to 4:00 p.m. EST. During these hours, it’s business as usual. Liquidity is high and spreads are low. \n\nBut when the lights go down in the city, things change. After hours, you’ll find: \n\nLess Liquidity – Sure, you may be in the mood to sell 100 shares of Starbucks (SBUX) at 2 a.m., but there may not be anyone in the mood to buy it at that hour. When there are fewer players in the game, you may have a harder time meeting your match in the markets. \n\nWider spreads – Fewer players means less trading volume. That leads to wider bid-ask spreads, and market prices may not come anywhere near what you’re looking to pay. \n\nHigher Volatility – If a company announces some hot news after market, demand in the stock could increase to a point where it overwhelms the number of after-hours traders who want to sell that same stock. As a result, share prices will spike dramatically. Then, once the market opens and more sellers show up to the party, the stock price could just as quickly tumble back to a fair level. \n\nThat doesn’t sound very fun…\n\nIt’s not all bad, of course! Here’s a great way to utilize after hours trading data: \n\nThink of it as a leading indicator for next trading-day activity in the stocks you own. Chances are if a stock makes big moves overnight, it will continue in the same direction the next day. \n\nIf you absolutely must have your fingers in the pie 24/7, then make sure to enter a limit order whenever you trade after hours. This will protect you from any wildly erratic price swings. \n\nBut, hey, the time between 4:00 p.m. and 9:30 a.m. EST is a good chunk of time to reflect, research and consider your strategy. \n\nSo in this case, we suggest going with the crowd and trading when the rest of the world is active, too.</string>
</resources>