<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="dgi_first_glance">• Invest in companies that you understand and believe in.\n• Use your own knowledge and that of your friends and family to discover great investing opportunities\n• Once you have a few companies in mind, you have to dig deeper to ensure they are well run businesses before investing. \n\nThe following chapters will give you some insight into how you can find great companies to invest in. These chapters are here to guide you as you start to think like an investor. \n\nBefore you actually buy shares, you’ll need to do a little more research to ensure they are well run businesses. \n\nPeter Lynch is widely regarded as one of the best investors of all time. He coined the idea of investing in what you know. \n\nThis mantra is central to the MyWallSt investing philosophy, but we take it one step further and say: “Buy what you believe in.” \n\nAs a consumer, you’ve spent your whole life interacting with businesses, whether it be large multinationals like Coca-Cola or your local grocery store. \n\nYour first step in finding great companies is to start looking at the companies that you, as a consumer, like. \n\nWhat brand of sporting wear do you buy? \n\nWhat food do you always have in your fridge? \n\nWhat websites do you visit most frequently? \n\nChances are a good deal of these are publicly listed companies that you can buy shares in. \n\nUse the knowledge from your own job. If you work in healthcare, you likely have industry knowledge that the rest of us don’t. If you work in IT, you probably know the best companies for network solutions, or cybersecurity, or e-commerce software. \n\nBut don’t stop there. Find out what companies your family and friends like. \n\nIf you have a friend who works in retail, ask what items are selling best. \n\nCheck out the lines outside the restaurants in your area. \n\nTake all this knowledge that is around you and come up with a list of companies that you are interested in. \n\nRemember, just because you like a company doesn’t mean it’s a good investment. To discover that, we’ll need to look a bit more closely.</string>
    <string name="dgi_company_culture">• Company culture refers to a company’s overall philosophy - how it treats its customers, how it rewards its employees, how it deals with environmental issues. \n• Studies have shown that companies with good culture greatly outperform the market. \n• Websites like Glassdoor.com can give you great insights into a company’s culture. \n\nAsk any Wall Street analyst what they look for in a good investment and they’ll rattle off earnings figures, growth numbers and ratios until you find a reason to excuse yourself. \n\nOf course, financial analysis is also important in choosing the right companies to invest in, but something that is very often overlooked is company culture. \n\nCompany culture covers so many aspects of a business; from its overall philosophy, to how it treats its customers, to how it rewards its employees - and it’s far more than just a nice idea. \n\nA recent study by Glassdoor.com found that company culture is incredibly important when it comes to returns for investors. \n\nThe study measured the performance of companies that ranked highly in Glassdoor’s “Best Places to Work” category, as well as those in Fortune 100’s “Best Companies to Work For” between 2009 and 2014. \n\nThe Fortune 100 companies outperformed the market by 84.2%, while Glassdoor’s own category outperformed by 115.6%. \n\nCompanies that ranked poorly in the category underperformed the market by 29.5% over the same time period. \n\nThat’s a huge difference and why we focus so much on good company culture in our showroom. \n\nSo how do you measure a company’s culture? \n\nGlassdoor.com is a great resource. There you can find company reviews from the employees themselves, as well as insights into how the CEO is viewed. Companies like Google, Facebook, Apple, Nike and Disney rank high on company culture overall, with Google being ranked “Best Place to Work” and “Best CEO.” \n\nChipotle, for example, has fostered the idea of “Food with Integrity.” \n\nCostco rewards loyalty by giving its customers huge discounts and its staff generous pay and benefits. Ever notice how much happier people are in Costco than Walmart? \n\nTesla is a company that puts purpose before profits. Elon Musk is more concerned with advancing sustainable transport than turning a quick buck, as shown by the move to open up their patents to competitors. You would think that would be a turnoff for investors, but on the contrary, Tesla has some of the most passionate and loyal investors, as well as customers.</string>
    <string name="dgi_visionary">• Visionary leaders can defy all expectations and create incredible businesses. \n• When you invest in a company, you are putting your faith in the CEO to deliver on your investment. \n• Do some research on the CEO and top officers in a business before investing. \n\nLike company culture, a visionary leader doesn’t show up anywhere on the balance sheet. \n\n However, this is one of the most important things you can look for when trying to identify a great investment. \n\nSo much of Wall Street is about looking for patterns, comparative analysis, and historical data. Visionary leaders are about breaking the pattern. Visionary leaders are incomparable. \n\nVisionary leaders can take businesses to heights never dreamed of before. \n\nSteve Jobs was a divisive figure. Some call him the Leonardo Da Vinci of our time, others think he was just a master marketer; either way, Steve Jobs changed the way in which all of us interact with technology. During his second stint at Apple, the stock rose over 2500%. \n\nJeff Bezos left a high paying job at a hedge fund to start an online bookstore. Through constant innovation, he has grown that idea into the e-commerce giant that is Amazon.com. Bezos was an earlier adopter of ‘predictive analysis’ - using our search history and buying habits to recommend products. That alone has transformed the way we utilize the internet. \n\nKevin Plank started selling sports apparel from his grandmother’s house in 1996. Twenty years later, Under Armour is the second largest apparel retailer in America. \n\nWhen you invest in a company, you’re betting the people in charge are going to grow your investment. \n\nBefore investing in a company, do a little research into the CEO. If that person was to personally approach you and ask to invest in their latest business venture, would you hand over your hard earned money? \n\nSome of the greatest innovators and thinkers are currently running publicly traded companies. With people like Bezos, Plank, Zuckerberg, Buffett and Musk to choose from, why settle for anything less than the best.</string>
    <string name="dgi_competitive">• Competitive advantage is an element that allows a business to outperform others. \n• Many businesses fail to innovate and lose their competitive advantage. \n• Beware of businesses that may become a target for giant competitors like Amazon. \n\nIt’s not always enough to have a great business, you need to have an edge on the competition. Competitive advantage describes an element of a business that allows it to outperform others, leading to greater sales, better margins, or higher customer retention. \n\nBorders had a great business once, but with the rise of the internet, they lost their competitive advantage to Amazon. \n\nBlockbuster Video was a huge money maker for half a century, but they failed to predict the rise of video streaming and were overtaken by Netflix. \n\nCompetitive advantage protects businesses from being swallowed up by others and can come in many forms. \n\nBrand names and trademarks are one of the strongest forms of competitive advantage. Someone could create a better tasting cola tomorrow, but they wouldn’t be able to topple Coca-Cola. \n\nWhen people want to search for information on the internet, they say they’ll “Google it.” That’s pretty incredible brand strength. \n\nCompetitive advantage can come in the form of patents. Companies like Facebook and Microsoft own patents on the technology they use to create their products and services. \n\nWhen looking for a good investment, always look for a sustainable competitive advantage. There are hundreds of new startups emerging everyday with new technologies or new approaches that can threaten even the biggest companies. \n\nWorse still, companies like Amazon can enter into your market with all the brand recognition and funding they need to wipe out a smaller competitor. In twenty years Amazon has gone from selling books, to electronics, to groceries and now to web services. \n\nIf you think they might go after the business you’re interested in, maybe think again.</string>
    <string name="dgi_evangelist">• An army of active brand advocates is a sign of a company’s competitive advantage. \n• The more people who recommend a brand to friends, the faster that brand will likely grow. \n• Start listening to which brands your friends are advocating in person and online. \n\nHave you ever been so enthralled with a new gadget that you had to tell everyone about it? Then tell them why they too need to get one right away? \n\nWhen a product or service lands in your life and makes it better than ever, it’s natural to promote that brand to your friends and family. \n\nIn this case, you’re known as a brand advocate, brand loyalist or brand enthusiast. \n\nWhichever name “evangelist” customers go by, they are an important part of a company’s growth and a great sign of staying power. \n\nOne simple question, “Would you recommend us to a friend?” is pure gold when it comes to business analytics. The more people that say yes, the freer, organic advertising a company gets. \n\nNowadays, companies are spending more money to get customers to answer yes to that question than they are on traditional advertising. \n\nHow does this tie into investing? \n\nIn addition to researching products and services that you like, start listening to what brands your friends are advocating. \n\nWhich brands do they like on Facebook? Which cell phone or internet company would they recommend you use? Is there a restaurant, clothing brand, or social network that gets people you know fired up when they talk about it? \n\nPay attention to these things. Studies have shown that the more willing customers are to recommend a product to their friends, the more likely the company will experience higher growth. \n\nAnd high-growth companies are exactly what you want in your portfolio.</string>
    <string name="dgi_industry">• A rapidly changing world brings new challenges and opportunities to businesses. \n• Long-term investors can take advantage of shifting global trends and emerging technologies\n• Be careful not to get caught up in overhyped stocks. \n\nThe world is changing faster than ever before. This brings new challenges and, with them, new opportunities for great businesses. New industries are popping up everywhere and a flurry of startup companies are competing for a share in the profits. \n\nA megatrend company is a leader in the industries of tomorrow, whether it be green energy, organic food, or even robotics. \n\nWhen we say you should buy what you believe in, that includes buying into the world you think is ahead of us. \n\nGood investors should always be forward thinking. Remember, we’re investing with a 5-10 year outlook. What will the world look like in ten years? \n\nWill McDonald’s still be the biggest fast food chain in the world, or will healthier alternatives continue to steal their market share? \n\nWill we be driving more electric cars? Will we even be driving them? Perhaps a computer will take over and let us sit back and relax on the highway. \n\nHow will drones affect our lives? Try to imagine the potential for online shopping or even food delivery if a drone can deliver something to your door in 30 minutes. \n\nWhat companies are going to profit from these social shifts? \n\nThis is the kind of thinking you should adopt if you want to prosper as a long term investor. \n\nYou’ll find great investing ideas by reading up on the latest technologies, changing consumer trends and the flurry of new services the internet has given birth to. \n\nBe conscious that new technologies often get overhyped in the early stages. Be careful not to throw money at the new “hot stocks” without properly evaluating the business and the market opportunity.</string>
</resources>