<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="dld_balance_sheets">• Balance sheets may appear complicated at first, but a few key figures can give you a good\n• idea of a company’s financial health. \n• In general, you want to see cash increasing, while debt and total shares should be decreasing. \n\nIf something appears unusual, investigate a little deeper - it’s important to understand the companies you are investing in. \n\nEach quarter, every public company is required to release a number of financial documents to give investors an overview of how the company is performing. \n\nOne such document is the balance sheet, which lists all the company’s assets and liabilities. You can find this on the company’s website (usually under Investor Relations) or on financial websites like Yahoo Finance. \n\nMany people get scared off by the prospect of having to read financial documents, but it doesn’t take a degree in business to be able to understand a few key figures. The first time you look at one, you may be overwhelmed, but as you grow as an investor, you’ll grow more comfortable with them. \n\nCash &amp; Cash Equivalents\n\nThis is the amount of cash the company has on hand. You can quickly check this figure against last year’s figure - if it’s going up, that’s a good sign. \n\nThat means the company is taking in and saving more money. This can be used to pay off debt, pay dividends, or grow the company. \n\nIf cash has gone down, try to find out why. It’s not always a bad sign. Perhaps the company put the money to good use. \n\nLong Term Debt\n\nIn the liabilities section you’ll see the company’s long term debt. Is this figure going down from previous years? That’s also a good sign. \n\nThis means management is making enough money to pay off their debt. \n\nDebt going up is usually a bad sign, but again, look a little deeper. Perhaps they borrowed in order to fund a great acquisition that will pay off further down the line. \n\nTotal Shares Outstanding\n\nThis is the amount of shares that are available for purchase right now. This includes the shares that were sold at the initial public offering and any other shares that have been issued since. If this figure is going down, that’s a good sign. \n\nThat shows that the company is buying back shares and retiring them. This means there is a bigger slice of the pie for each individual shareholder. \n\nIn a young growth company, you will usually find this number increasing. This isn’t a bad sign, as young companies need to raise capital, usually by issuing more shares. \n\nNo one figure on a balance sheet will tell you if a company is a good investment or not. A balance sheet is useful for getting an overview of where the company stands and can highlight further avenues to explore before you invest.</string>
    <string name="dld_ownership">• “Insiders” are CEOs, officers and board members. \n• If they own company stock, their interests are aligned with shareholder interests. \n• Look out for companies with insider ownership of over 5%.\n\nInsider Buying &amp; Selling\n\nYou can read all the financial reports and prospectuses you can get your hands on, but there will always be people who know more than you ever will about whether or not a company is a good investment: the insiders. \n\nAnd, thankfully, insiders are also investors in their companies just like we are. This is a good thing for two reasons: \n\nWhen insiders own stock, their interests are the same as ours, so we can logically assume that their actions are geared towards increasing shareholder value. \n\nWe can monitor their buying and selling patterns to try and get a read on the direction the company is heading. \n\nInsiders, by definition, are officers and directors with a stake in the company. They are the folks at the top making the big, corporate-wide decisions. \n\nHere at MyWallSt, we like to see insiders with a greater than 5% ownership in the business they’re paid to run. \n\nYou’ll usually find that the older a company is, the lower the insider ownership. \n\nYou can find this information in the “Key Statistics” section on financial websites like Yahoo Finance. \n\nWhen to Take Notice\n\nFrom H. Nejat Seyhun’s book Investment Intelligence from Insider Trading we learn when to sit up and take notice of insider buying and selling: \n\n1. The higher up on the corporate food chain the trades are happening, the more you should care. In order of most noteworthy to least, it goes CEO > officer > board member. \n2. Insider buying is a better signifier of things to come than insider selling. Selling can happen for any number of reasons, and often it’s because the top brass is exercising their options, which is a very common form of executive compensation. Some people may want to make a big deal out of insider sells, but often it’s just “noise.” \n3. When insiders are buying and selling, make note of recent share price movement. If they are buying shares while the price is rising, this is usually a sign that they expect it to keep rising. Conversely, if they’re selling while prices are in decline, they may be trying to protect themselves from further losses. \n\nThe number of shares an insider is selling matters. Pay attention if they’re buying or selling somewhere between 10,000 and 100,000 shares. Anything above or below that number isn’t usually cause for concern. \n\nThere you have it… now, when the financial talking heads start squawking about insider buying and selling, you can take a few steps back and see if it\'s really anything that concerns you as a shareholder.</string>
    <string name="dld_cash_flow">• Positive cash flow means that for a period of time, more money came in than went out. \n• Positive cash flow can fund a company’s growth even if the company is losing money. \n• When a company is cash flow positive, they are in control of their future. \n\nPositive Cash Flow\n\nPeople talk a lot about a company being profitable or not. In reality, you wouldn’t expect young growth companies to be profitable, but that doesn’t mean they aren’t making plenty of money. \n\nPositive cash flow means that for a certain period of time, more money came in than went out. It does not mean, however, that the company is profitable. \n\nCash-flow statements show the actual money flowing in and out of a company’s bank account. One look and you can see whether the company is “generating cash” or “burning cash.” \n\nWhen a company is cash flow positive; they have control over their future. A negative cash flow means either raising money or eventually going bust. \n\nPositive cash flow is usually a result of diligent governance over cash inflows and expenditure. That’s what we want to see – smart, strategic management! \n\nIt can also stem from a company’s business model. Take Groupon (GRPN), for example. \n\nIf Suzy goes to Groupon.com and buys a $10 coupon for $20 worth of nail care, Groupon collects her $10 on the spot. Then, months later Suzy redeems her Groupon. Sometime after that, Groupon remits a portion of Suzy’s $10 to the salon. \n\nGroupon does this thousands of times a day – collecting cash from its subscribers long before it pays the merchants. That creates positive cash flow. \n\nIn turn, positive cash flow can fund the company’s growth even if the company is losing money. \n\nSo, when exploring companies to invest in, remember that the cash-flow statements throwing off the most positive vibes are worth a second look.</string>
    <string name="dld_cash_debt">• Look for companies with more cash than debt. \n• Market Cap – Cash + Debt = Enterprise value\n• Enterprise value is more accurate than market cap when determining a company’s value.\n\nMore Cash than Debt\n\nIt’s nearly impossible for a person, company or country to go belly up when they’ve got more cash than debt. \n\nAs a smart investor, keeping personal debt under control is crucial for your financial well-being. Same goes for the companies you invest in. \n\nSure, it’s completely normal for companies to borrow money to fund their rise to greatness. \n\nBut, at MyWallSt, we look for companies that are able to pay off all of their obligations. It’s a very important indicator of a business’ health. \n\nEnterprise Value vs. Market Cap\n\nAn easy way to figure out if a company is cash-positive is by calculating a company’s enterprise value. \n\nBasically, if enterprise value is less than market cap, then the business has more cash than debt. \n\nEnterprise Value = Market Cap – Cash + Debt. \n\nHere’s what that formula means: \n\nMarket capitalization (total number of shares in existence multiplied by the current share price) is roughly how much money you’d need to buy the entire business. \n\nBut when you buy a business you’re also getting its cash and its debt. Enterprise value takes this into account by using the formula above. It offers a clearer picture of a company’s financial well-being. \n\nYou don’t need to calculate enterprise value yourself. It will usually be listed in the “Key Statistics” section on financial websites. Alternatively, you can simply look at a company’s balance sheet and see if they have more cash than long-term debt.</string>
    <string name="dld_spending_money">• Return on Equity (ROE) tells you how well management is using investors’ money. \n• Anywhere between 15% to 20% ROE is considered good. \n• ROE is useful for comparing companies in the same industry. \n\nReturn on Equity\n\nAs a shareholder, you are part-owner of a business, but you still don’t get to sit down with the CFO and ask where your money is being spent. \n\nLuckily, there is a metric known as Return on Equity (ROE) that gives you a pretty good idea of how the top brass is handling your cash. \n\nROE tells you how effective a company is at using shareholder capital (the money you gave in exchange for stocks) to generate profits. \n\nReturn On Equity = Net Income ÷ Shareholder Equity\n\nROE is especially useful for comparing the profitability of companies in the same industry, like Coke (KO) and Pepsi (PEP) or American Eagle (AEO) and Abercrombie (ANF). \n\nAnywhere between 15% to 20% ROE is considered good and that’s what we aim for when looking for companies to invest in. This means that for every dollar invested, the company generated 15 to 20 cents in profit. \n\nBut high ROE doesn’t have any immediate benefit. The benefit comes from a company with a high ROE rate reinvesting their earnings back into the company. This, in turn, gives the company a high growth rate, which is what you want to see as a shareholder. \n\nWhen researching a company, if you find a CFO bragging about “record earnings” in a year, it’s smart to check their ROE as well. That will tell you not just how much more the company is bringing in, but also whether or not management is playing smart with reinvesting those increased funds.</string>
    <string name="dld_sales_growth">• Don’t compare this month’s sales to the previous, compare them to the same month last year. \n• Scope out companies experiencing 15% year over year (YOY) sales growth. \n• You can find YOY sales figures in a company’s quarterly earnings report. \n\nGrow, stock, grow! \n\nFor your investment to grow, the company’s sales have to grow. \n\nAnd just like other criteria we use when looking at stocks to buy, we think it’s important to set a benchmark for the minimum year over year (YOY) sales growth. \n\nWhile 12% is a pretty impressive number, we here at MyWallSt say shoot for the stars and scope out companies experiencing 15% YOY sales growth. \n\n“How do I Figure out This Percentage?” \n\n(Current Period Sales – Previous Period Sales) ÷ Previous Period Sales = Year Over Year Percentage Sales Growth\n\n(Multiply that final number by 100 or just move the decimal point two places to the right to get the percentage) \n\n"How Can I Use This Formula?" \n\nBusinesses can be seasonal, so if a company is doing more sales in June than they were the month before, don’t be fooled into thinking they are growing. \n\nTake a look at how they were doing LAST June and use the formula above to calculate the percentage they have changed since the same time last year. \n\nThis is especially true when looking at automotive stocks like Ford (F) or General Motors (GM). If you compared April sales to May sales, you would probably see a huge spike. \n\nIs that the sign of a huge growth trend that will continue? Probably not. \n\nMay is generally always the biggest car-buying month, because people like to use their tax returns to put a down payment on a new ride. \n\nSo the better way to check out growth is comparing this May to last May instead. Or even, as is often done, comparing this quarter to the same quarter last year. \n\n“But, I’m no Good With Formulas!” \n\nOften, you won’t even need to use this formula, because it’s already been calculated for you by company management. A good place to find it is to read the transcript of a company’s quarterly earnings call. They’re usually widely available online. Simply do an Internet search for “Ticker symbol + earnings call transcript.” \n\nRemember, 12% is good… 15% is better… and if a company’s “growing season” is year-round, that’s the absolute best.</string>
</resources>