<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="prologue">Today you’ve taken a huge step towards improving your financial future and we’re here to help you on that journey.\n\nI’ve been investing in U.S. stocks for over 20 years. I made many mistakes as a young investor and got hit hard when the Dot Com bubble burst. But I learned from those mistakes, dedicated my life to investing in great businesses, and am a far wealthier person today for it — both financially and personally.\n\nIf you’ve just downloaded Learn, you’re likely watching the current market turmoil and want some guidance on how you can benefit from this. You’re following in the path of over two million people around the world who have already decided to take control of their finances and enrich themselves through this app.\nOver the last 20 years, my portfolio has grown 21% on average per year. That may not sound like a lot, but thanks to compounding (which you will learn about shortly), those returns would turn $10,000 into over $450,000. Not everyone will achieve such amazing results. However, this is what is possible if you commit to long-term buy-and-hold investing and follow some very simple rules.\nThere are many different ways to invest your money and you can customize your strategy to suit your personal situation and tolerance for risk. Our goal here is to teach you the fundamentals of great investing so that you can make better decisions and own your financial future. The content in this app was first written over five years ago and since then, very little has changed. These lessons are timeless and are applicable to any market conditions.\nBy the time you finish this course, I’m certain you will be ready to start your investing journey — in whatever form that takes.</string>
    <string name="why_stock">• Owning stock means owning a piece of a company.\n• Invested funds are working for you 24/7.\n• Invested money can grow much faster than cash in a savings account.\n\nEver wanted to own part of a great business? That’s exactly what happens when you purchase stock. You’re buying a part of that company. As a part owner, you’re entitled to a share of the profits and assets of that business.\n\nYou profit from owning stock in one of two ways.\n1. The company can decide to return money to their shareholders via dividends. This is cash that is paid to you on a regular basis for being a shareholder.\n2. The business grows and the price per share increases. Once you decide to sell your shares, you pocket the returns.\n\nWhile money kept in a savings account gets eaten away by inflation, invested money is working for you 24/7. Unlike a bank account, your original outlay can multiply many times over if you invest in the right companies.\n\nOn average, the stock market has returned around 10% annually since 1974 (without factoring in inflation). That easily beats the 0.5% you’ll get by keeping your money in a savings account.</string>
    <string name="financial_goals">• Investing: Start small, but start now!\n• $2,000 can turn into almost $100,000 after 40 years (at 10% return a year).\n• Investing in stocks can help you pay for your biggest goals.\n\nThat 10% average increase may not sound like much, but given time, this interest compounds to produce incredible returns.\n\nImagine someone told you that you could turn $2,000 into $100,000 with no work whatsoever? It sounds too good to be true, but it’s completely possible if you understand compound interest (which will be discussed in the next lesson).\n\nThe key element to remember here is time. The longer you have your money invested, the more powerful compounding becomes. That means the younger you get started, and the more patient you are, the greater returns you will reap in the future.\n\nHowever, you don’t need $2,000 to get started. You can start small and keep adding to your investment over time. You’ll be amazed how quickly your investment can grow. In fact, if you added $100 a month to that initial $2,000 investment, after 40 years you’d have close to $1 million.\n\nYou’ll have both winners and losers, but if you learn how to identify good companies, you’ll have some stocks that multiply 10 times (or more) in value over the years.\n\nThe biggest advantage you can give yourself is to start early and let that compounding work its magic.</string>
    <string name="compound_magic">• Compound interest is when the money you earn starts earning money.\n• Compounding is the easiest way to become wealthy.\n• The sooner you begin investing, the more time your earnings have to compound.\n\nCompound interest is an investor’s best friend. Compounding is simply when the money you earn starts earning money. This means your stash is growing faster than if you were simply adding a lump sum every month.\n\nSo many people say “I can’t afford to start investing.” The truth is, you can’t afford not to start investing, because time is the issue here, not money. Compound interest is the real silver bullet when it comes to growing your wealth and the earlier you start, the more powerful it becomes.\n\nA certificate of deposit (CD) or a government bond over time might give you 5% per year. A 10% annual return is the historical average for the stock market. And 15% is what you could get if you learn how to pick your own stocks and take advantage of the skills MyWallSt teaches.\n\nThe majority of people subscribe to some form of online entertainment service like Spotify Premium or Netflix – a lot subscribe to both. The $18 leaves our bank accounts every month and we hardly even notice.\n\nLet’s say at 18 years old, you subscribe to both services and remain a loyal customer for the next 50 years. You’ll end up retiring $10,800 down. “Small price to pay for being able to binge watch Breaking Bad,” I hear you say.\n\nHad you stuck that $18 into a savings account instead you’d have that $10,800 when it comes to retiring, plus some interest. Of course, inflation will have eaten up a huge chunk of that, so it’s hardly worth giving up the comfort and convenience of your subscription accounts.\n\nHad you invested that money, after year one, on average, you’re up 10% on your original investment. The year after, you make interest on your interest and so on. It’s like adding successive layers to a cake with each a little larger than the last. So if you’d consistently invested that money, after 50 years it would be worth over $300,000.\n\nStill think you can’t afford to start?</string>
    <string name="pay_yourself">• Saving 10% of your total income is a good goal.\n• Set up automatic transfers into savings on the day you get your paycheck.\n• If you pay yourself first, you won’t even notice there’s less money to spend.\n\nNow that we’ve decided that you can afford to start, how do you go about building up that investment fund?\n\nIf you’re someone who has trouble saving money, this is where the biggest change is going to have to come. You can’t invest without being a disciplined saver.\n\nInstead of saving what you don’t spend, spend what you don’t save.\n\nThink of this as investing in yourself. You need to learn to pay yourself first.\n\nYou already pay the companies behind your credit card, gas, water, electric, cable, and phone bills every month, right? Now, add yourself to the list\n\nSo how much should you pay yourself?\n\nAim for 10% of your total income, but anything is better than nothing. It may seem like a lot to those who struggle every month to pay the bills, but the less you have at hand, the less you’ll spend. Set up automatic transfers so your savings leave your account as soon as you get paid. You’ll be amazed at how fast you can adapt to spending a little bit less.\n\nIdeally, you should be investing this money in the stock market, where its 10% average annual returns and compounding can begin building your wealth. However, if you know you’re going to need that money in the near future, it’s better to keep it in cash. This will ensure you don’t have to sell your investments prematurely and lose money in a down market.\n\nOnce you’ve built up a cushion of emergency money, you can start investing.</string>
    <string name="steps_to_saving">• Every dollar is an investment in the quality of your life.\n• Build a cash cushion of 3–12 months of income before you invest.\n• Track your spending by writing it down or using online tools to help you.\n\nHaving a cash cushion is an important step before you start investing. Though it’s natural to want to jump right in and get your money in the market, this can be dangerous. A successful investor understands that over the short term your investments may lose money.\n\nWe recommend a long-term buy and hold philosophy when it comes to investing. If you put all your cash into the market, you may end up needing it in the near future. The market could be down at that stage, meaning you’ll have to sell your investments for a loss. If you have a cash cushion, you can leave your investments intact and wait for a recovery.\n\nYou should therefore try to build up a cash cushion of at least three months salary.\n\nThis may sound difficult, but it’s easy to train yourself to save money, and once you get in the habit of doing so, you’ll enjoy seeing your account balance go up every month.\n\n<b>Step 1</b>\n\nRetire short term debt\n\nIf you’re paying a high interest rate on credit cards, you need to retire that debt. You can’t build long term wealth while paying up to 20% on short term debt.\n\n<b>Step 2</b>\n\nTreat every dollar like an investment.\n\nThis is a crucial mind frame to get into if you wish to become a successful investor. An investment is more than just shares. We make investments every day. Some of these are important, like the roof over our head. Some of these are frivolous, like a new pair of sneakers you don’t really need.\n\nNext time you pull out your credit card, ask yourself, “Is this the best investment I can make with this money right now?” You won’t put your wallet away every time you do this, but just practicing this routine can help you save a lot of money.\n\n<b>Step 3</b>\n\nTrack your spending.\n\nEver come to the end of the month and wonder where all your hard-earned money went? It happens to us all now and then.\n\nA good way to counter this is to start tracking your spending. There are plenty of apps available to keep tabs on where your money is going. You might be shocked to realize how much you spend simply on going out for lunch every day, or on getting that extra cup of coffee from Starbucks.\n\nThese are small changes you can make that can greatly increase your overall wealth.</string>
    <string name="timeline">• If you need money in the next year, it should be in cash.\n• Any money that you don’t need in the next year should be invested.\n• You should invest with a 5–10 year timeline in mind.\n\nGo Long!\n\nWhen choosing how much money to invest in the stock market, it’s important to consider how long it will be before you need that cash.\n\nHere are two rules of thumb to follow when deciding the smartest, safest and most profitable place for your savings.\n\n<B>Rule 1</B>\n\n“If you need your money in the next year, it should be in cash.”\n\nThe stock market can fluctuate greatly. It’s no fun to need cash for, say, a down payment on your first home and find that your stocks are down 50%.\n\nIf you’re house shopping, wedding planning or car buying within the next year, keep those necessary funds in a savings or money market account. (Double check that it’s FDIC-insured too.)\n\n<b>Rule 2</b>\n\n"Any money you don’t need within the next year is a candidate for the stock market."\n\nThis is where the fun begins. And it’s why we encourage you to get saving now!\n\nAny cash you don’t need in the coming year can go to work for you every day in the stock market… taking bigger risks and affording you larger profits.\n\nWhen you invest with funds that you have no immediate need for, you protect yourself from the short term fluctuations of the stock market. Over the course of a year or two, you could see your investment suffer a loss, but on a longer timeline, the stock market and great companies get bigger and more profitable.\n\nThat’s why you should invest with a 5–10 year timeline in mind. This will prevent you from pulling your funds out in a downturn and incurring a loss.</string>
</resources>